Finding aid for the Gene Roddenberry Star Trek Television Series Collection PASC.0062
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gene Roddenberry Star trek television series collection
1966-1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC.0062
18.0 Linear Feet (36 boxes)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942336793606533
Biography
"Star Trek" debuted in 1966 and ran to 79 episodes; it started with low ratings, but the support of its audience and science fiction writers prevented its cancellation; the show was launched by Gene Roddenberry with a format similar to that of Wagon train, a weekly television program about pioneers traveling westward; over time Roddenberry and "Star Trek" acquired a following of loyal fans, known as "Trekkies"; "Star Trek" reruns in the late 1970s prompted the continued popularity of the series; Paramount pictures produced several "Star Trek" movies starring the original television series cast; Roddenberry created and became executive producer for another television series called "Star Trek: The Next Generation," which was set seventy-eight years after the final "Star Trek" episode.
Eugene Wesley Roddenberry was born in El Paso, TX, Aug. 19, 1921; AA, Los Angeles City College, 1941; attended Univ. of CA, LA, Univ. of Miami, and Columbia Univ.; second lieutenant, US Army Air Forces, 1941-45; Pan American Airways, pilot, 1945-49; LA Police Dept., LA, CA 1949-53; started his career as television and motion picture creator, producer, and writer in 1953; president of Norway Production, Inc, (1962-); member of various professional organizations including the Writers Guild of America, West and the Academy of Television Arts and Sciences; in addition to his television credits, he was involved with several "Star Trek" motion pictures; published "Star Trek: The Motion Picture" (1979), The making of "Star Trek: The Motion Picture" (1980), and "Star Trek: The First Twenty-Five Years" (1991); the recipient of numerous awards; died in LA, CA, Oct. 24, 1991.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of material related to the television program, Star trek. Includes story outlines, treatments and various drafts of scripts, shooting schedules, cast lists, title sheets, photographic lists, budget reports, and memoranda.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Produced episodes
Correspondence/general files
Unproduced materials
Television producers and directors -- Archives.; Television writers -- Archives.; Roddenberry, Gene--Archives.
- PRODUCED EPISODES
  - ALL OUR YESTERDAYS (Prod# 78)
    - 1) Story Outline by Jean Lisette Aroeste, 9/23/68, 6 pgs. 2) Revised story outline, 10/27/68, 13 pgs. 3) First draft teleplay, 11/18/68, 55 pgs. 4) Second draft teleplay, 11/26/68, 52 pgs. 5) Final draft teleplay, 12/12/68, 70 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Aroeste, Jean Lisette (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (4). Total Items: 4 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 10/8/68 - 12/20/68. Total Items: 6 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bays, Donald W. * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Production Materials: Shooting Schedule (6), Photographic Effects (3), Daily Production Reports (3), Call Sheets (4). Total Items: 16 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (3), Estimated Finished Budget (3). Total Items: 31 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - THE ALTERNATIVE FACTOR (Prod# 20)
    - 1) Treatment by Don Ingalls, 8/29/66, 12 pgs., 2 copies 2) Treatment, 9/12/66, 15 pgs, 2 copies. 3) Treatment, 9/14/66, 15 pgs., 2 copies. 3) First draft teleplay, 10/14/66, 66 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Ingalls, Don (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (103), Notes on story premise (1), Notes on story outline (1, 2 copies), Notes on 1st draft teleplay (2, 2 copies), DeForest Research (5, 2 copies). Total Items: 120 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Production Materials: Shooting Schedule (9, 2 copies), Cast List (3, 2 copies), Call Sheets (14), Daily Production Reports (7), Credits (3). Total Items: 48 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 9/2/66 - 12/22/66. Total Items: 35 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * D'Agosta, Joe * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Coon, Gene (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Report (3). Total Items: 3 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - AMOK TIME (Prod# 34)
    - 1) Story Outline by Theodore Sturgeon, 12/12/66, 10 pgs. (2 copies) 2) Story Outline, 12/12/66, 11 pgs. (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (5), Notes on new story (1, 2 copies). Total Items: 7 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 12/15/66 - 6/1/67, 8/16/67. Total Items: 44 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Nimoy, Leonard * Roddenberry, Gene * Coon, Gene * Justman, Robert * Fontana, D.C. * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Reports (2), Daily Cost Reports (8). Total Items: 10 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - AND THE CHILDREN SHALL LEAD (Prod# 60)
    - 1) Story Outline by Edward J. Lasko, 3/11/68, 15 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 3/18/68, 17 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 3/22/68, w/annotations, 16 pgs. 4) Teleplay, 4/8/68, w/annotations, 65 pgs. 5) Teleplay, 4/18/68, 65 pgs. 6) Teleplay, 4/30/68, 65 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Lasko, Edward J. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (7). Total Items: 7 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/13/68 - 7/29/68. Total Items: 25 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Dewey, Ray * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Shooting Schedule (10), Photographic Effects (4), Daily Production Report (7), Call Sheets (6). Total Items: 30 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (18), Estimated Finish Cost (28). Total Items: 71 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - THE APPLE (Prod# 38)
    - 1) Story Outline by Max Ehrlich, 5/2/67, 16 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 5/4/67, 15 pgs. (2 copies, 1 w/annotations) 3) Story Outline, 4/10/67, 9 pgs. (with premises by A.E. Van Vogt) 4) 1st draft teleplay, 5/29/67, 63 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Ehrlich, Max (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (4), Revisions, loose pages (12). Total Items: 16 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Production Materials: Credits (1). Total Items: 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/11/67 - 7/20/67. Total Items: 71 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bay, Don R. * Messerschmidt, Jean * Fontana, D.C. * Justman, Robert * Coon, Gene * Roddenberry, Gene * Robertson, Stanley (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Financial Materials: Daily Status Reports (7). Total Items: 7 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - ARENA (Prod# 19)
    - 1) Story Outline by Gene Coon, 10/10/66, 11 pgs. 2) Revised First Draft teleplay, 10/18/66, w/annotations, 56 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Coon, Gene (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (20), DeForest Research (6). Total Items: 26 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Production Materials: Shooting Schedule (10), Cast List (2), Call Sheet (6), Daily Production Reports (5) Credits (3). Total Items: 26 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 10/14/66 - 11/14/66: Total items: 14. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Robertson, Stanley (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Report (4), Daily Budget Report (1). Total Items: 5 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - ASSIGNMENT: EARTH (Prod# 55)
    - 1) Story Outline by Gene Roddenberry, n.d., w/annot., 8 pgs. 2) Story Outline by Gene Roddenberry & Art Wallace, n.d., 22 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 10/21/67, w/annot., 23 pgs. 4) Story Outline, 10/21/67, 22 pgs. 5) Story Outline, 11/13/67, 22 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Wallace, Art (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 1) Teleplay Outline, 4 pgs, w/annot., 3 copies. 2) Pilot Teleplay, 11/14/66, 5 pgs. (Incomp.) 3) Teleplay, 11/14/66, 13 pgs. (Incomp.) 4) Teleplay, 11/14/66, w/annot., 16 pgs. (Incomp.) 5) Teleplay, 11/14/66, 36 pgs. (Incomp.) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 1) 1st draft teleplay, 11/14/66, w/annot., 27 pgs. (Incomp.) 2) 1st draft teleplay, 11/14/66, 27 pgs. (Incomp.) 3) 1st draft teleplay, 11/14/66, 45 pgs. 4) 1st draft teleplay, n.d., 76 pgs. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - 1) First draft teleplay, 11/14/66, w/annotations, 44 pgs. 2) First draft teleplay, 11/14/66, w/annotations, 46 pgs. 3) Teleplay, 11/21/67, 36 pgs. (Incomplete) 4) Teleplay, 11/21/67, 81 pgs. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (55), DeForest Research (16), Story Notes (2), List of Seven's Gadgets (2), Narrative (2). Total Items: 77 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, Paramount Television, ACE Books, Inc., Tony Ford Management, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 12/27/67 - 3/13/68. Total Items: 184 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Wallace, Art * Justman, Robert * D'Agosta, Joe * Katz, Marvin * Freedman, David * Robertson, Stanley * Lavery, Emmet * Fontana, D.C. * Solow, Herb * Perlstein, Ed * Patten, Fred * Ford, Tony * Carr, Terry * Milkis, Ed * Whitaker, Walter E. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3), Stock Footage Breakdowns (25), Dubbing Schedule (1), Cast List (2), Daily Production Reports (6), Call Sheet (6), Vault Transporter Sequences (3), Automated Dialogue Dubbing Cue Sheets (6). Total Items:52 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Overview (1), Budget and Cost Report {Spinoff Budget} (4), Budget Worksheets {Spinoff Budget} (4), Budget and Cost Report (4), Budget Worksheets (31), Daily Cost Status Reports (7). Total Items: 51 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - BALANCE OF TERROR (Prod# 9)
    - Drafts of episodes by Paul Schneider: 1) Preliminary draft, n.d., 70 pages. 2) First draft, 06/21/66, with annotations, 70 pages. 3) Revised final draft, 7/18/66, 66 pages, with annotations. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Schneider, Paul (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1) Story outline by Paul Schneider, 4/14/66, 31 pages 2) Story outline, n.d., with annotations, 23 pages. 3) Story outline, 4/26/66, 23 pages. 3) Story outline, n.d., with annotations, 23 pages. 4) Story outline, n.d., 1 pg. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1) Notes on meeting w/Paul Schneider, 5 pgs. 2) DeForest Research, 1 pg. 3) Voice Over lines, 1 pg. 4) Script, loose pages, 31 pgs. 5) Script, loose pages, 15 pgs. Total Items:53 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1) Rev. script, loose pages, 12 pgs. 2) Rev. script, loose pages, 9 pgs. 3) Rev. script, loose pages, 3 pgs. Total Items: 24 pgs. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Production materials: Shooting schedule (11), Cast list (3), Cast Sheet (1), Call sheets (7), Daily production reports (6), Work Orders (5), Rough cut comments (1), Production comments (1), Credits (3, 4 copies). Total Items: 47 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Financial Materials: Daily budget reports (7), Photo Effects (1), Production budget report (2). Total Items: 10 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence/Inter-Office Memos: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 4/18/66 - 7/29/66. Notes on Teleplay (7). Total Items: 40 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Posivak, Tom * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - BREAD AND CIRCUSES (Prod# 43)
    - 1) Story Outline by John Kneubuhl, n.d., 5 pgs. 2) Outline for NBC, 3/17/67, 4 pgs. 3) Story Outline, 3/17/67, 8 pgs. 4) Final draft teleplay by John Kneubuhl and Gene Coon, 8/15/67, ? pgs., Incomplete Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Kneubuhl, John (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Script Materials: Staff comments on Story Outline (3), DeForest Research (14). Total Items: 17 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/14/67 - 9/19/67. Total Items: 58 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Fontana, D.C. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Report (1), Budget Work Sheets (24). Total Items:25 (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - BY ANY OTHER NAME (Prod# 50)
    - 1) Revised story outline, 6/26/67, 18 pgs. 3) Final Draft teleplay, 10/31/67, w/annotations. 38 pgs. (Incomplete) 4) Teleplay, 11/7/67, 39 pgs. (Incomplete) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (5). Total Items: 5 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 5/8/67 - 10/18/67. Total Items: 76 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Fontana, D.C. * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Coon, Gene * Robertson, Stanley (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - CATSPAW (Prod# 30)
    - 1) Treatment by Robert Bloch, 3/9/67, w/annotations, 16 pgs. 2) Story Outline, 3/14/67, 17 pgs. 3) Teleplay, 3/29/67, 66 pgs. 4) 2nd draft teleplay, 4/14/67, w/annotations, 59 pgs. (Incomplete) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bloch, Robert (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (4), DeForest Research (1). Total Items: 5 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Production materials: Optical-miniature list (1). Total Items: 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/24/67 - 4/27/67. Total Items: 31 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Fontana, D.C. * Robertson, Stanley (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Financial Materials: Contract request form - writer (1), Production Budget Reports (10). Total Items: 11 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - THE CHANGELING (Prod# 37)
    - 1) Revised Story outline by John Meredyth Lucas, 3/15/67, 28 pgs. 2) Story outline, 3/15/67, 29 pgs. (2 copies) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Lucas, John Meredyth (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Script Materials: Staff Comments (3), DeForest Research (7). Total Items: 10 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/17/67 - 6/1/67. Total Items: 63 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Coon, Gene * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Financial Materials: Contract Request Form (1), Production Budget Reports (2), Daily Cost Reports (6). Total Items: 9 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - CHARLIE X (Prod# 8)
    - Teleplay by D. C. Fontana, story by Gene Roddenberry. 1) Second draft, 6/27/66, 68 pages. 2) Final draft, 7/5/66, 66 pages, with annotation. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Story outlines, no author: 1) 4/18/66, 6 pages. 2) 4/18/66, 5 pages, 3) 4/23/66, 5 pages. 3) Treatment by D.C. Fontana, 4/27/66, 21 pages (2 copies) and May 9, 1966, 23 pages. 4) ACT I "Charlie Is God", 8/28/64, 6 pages. (2 copies). 84 items. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Script materials: Rev. pages, 7/13/66. Lyrics by G. Roddenberry "Charlie is My Darling". Synopsis, 1p. Cutting notes on first cut, 8/8/66. Notes on sound effects. Research Notes/DeForest Research, 07/12/66. Kirk's voice over. Draft, n.d. 72 pages Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Production materials: shooting schedule, cast list, call sheets (07/01/66 - 07/19/66), daily production reports (07/11/66 - 07/19/66), Credits Breakdown (3, 4 copies). Total Items: 38 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and inter-department memos, Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company. NBC Broadcast Standards Dept. Report. 19 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials: Production budget reports, 10 items. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - THE CITY ON THE EDGE OF FOREVER (Prod# 28)
    - 1) Treatment by Cordwainer Bird, 3/21/66, 17 pgs. (2 copies, 1 w/annotations) 2) Treatment by Harlan Ellison, 5/13/66, w/annotations, 22 pgs. 3) Treatment by Harlan Ellison, 5/13/66, 24 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Ellison, Harlan (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - 1) Teleplay by Harlan Ellison, 6/3/66, 59 pgs. 2) Revised final draft teleplay by Harlan Ellison, 8/12/66, w/annotations, 58 pgs. (2 copies, 1 copy missing last page) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - 1) Treatment, 12/29/66, 13 pgs. 2) First draft teleplay by Steve Corabatsos, n.d., 67 pgs. 3) Teleplay by Harlan Ellison, 1/23/67, 71 pgs. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1) Teleplay, n.d., 70 pgs. 2) Teleplay by Harlan Ellison, n.d., w/annotations, 59 pgs. (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (109). Nationa Standard Department (1). Total Items: 110 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3, 2 copies), Call Sheets (4), Daily Production Report (1), Cast list (2), Shooting schedule (2),. Total items: 15 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Financial Materials: Production Budget Reports (2). Total Items: 2 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - THE CLOUD MINDERS (Prod# 74)
    - 1) Rev. Treatment by Armen, 8/2/68, 14 pgs. 2) Outline, 8/14/68, 12 pgs. 3) 1st draft teleplay, 9/27/68, 60 pgs. 4) 2nd draft teleplay, 10/21/68, w/annot., 75 pgs. 5) Polish Teleplay, 11/7/68, w/annot., 79 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Armen, Margaret * Crawford, Oliver * Gerrold, David (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - 1) Story Outline by Oliver Crawford and David Gerrold, 6/24/68, 15 pgs. 2) Revised Story Outline, 7/10/68, 11 pgs. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (7). Total Items: 7 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 8/23/68 - 12/10/68. Total Items: 6 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bays, Donald W. * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Production Materials: Photographic Effects (3), Daily Production Reports (7), Call Sheets (5). Total Items: 15 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (7), Estimated Finished Cost (8). Total Items: 40 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - THE CONSCIENCE OF THE KING (Prod# 13)
    - 1) Story outline by Barry Trivers, n.d., 6 pgs. 2) Rough layout by Barry Trivers, n.d., 7 pgs. 3) 2nd draft teleplay by Barry Trivers, 6/8/66, w/annotations, 69 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Trivers, Barry (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (85), Comments on teleplay (5), DeForest Research (5). Total Items: 95 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Production materials: Credits (3, 3 copies), Shooting schedule (9), Cast list (3), Call sheets (7), Daily production reports (9), Work Order (1). Total Items: 38 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 4/14/66 - 10/19/66. Total Items: 68 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Perlstein, Ed * Roddenberry, Gene * Black, John D.F. * Robertson, Stanley (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Financial materials: Production budget reports (4), Photo effects (1), Daily budget reports (6). Total Items: 11 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - THE CORBOMITE MANEUVER (Prod# 3)
    - 1) Treatment, by Jerry Sohl, n.d., 25 pages, 2 copies. 2) Treatment, n.d., 17 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sohl, Jerry (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1) 1st draft teleplay, by Jerry Sohl, 4/21/66, 64 pages. 2) Revised draft, n.d., with annotations, 52 pgs. (missing pgs 49 - 56). Page 53 and 54 with set building description. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Script Materials: Voice Over, Wild Lines (3), Replacement line (1), Notes on revised outline (1), DeForest Research (5). paotal Items: 10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Production Materials: Shooting schedule (11), Cast list (2), Casting appointment schedule (1), Call sheets (9), Daily production reports (9), Credits (3, 4 copies), Revised Credits (3, 3 copies), Editing Notes (4). Total Items: 57 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence/Inter-Office Memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/4/66 - 8/4/66. Total Items: 28 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Rode, Don * Roddenberry, Gene * Robertson, Stanley * Theiss, Bill * Jefferies, Matt * Kubichan, Jon (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Photographs (4). Total Items: 4 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Financial materials: Photo effects (2), Production budget reports (2), Daily budget reports (7). Total Items: 11 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - COURT MARTIAL (Prod# 15)
    - 1) Story Outline by Don M. Mankiewicz, 5/2/66, w/annotations, 10 pgs. 2) Revised Outline by Mankiewicz, 6/26/66, 11 pgs. 3) Teleplay, 7/15/66, 69 pgs. 4) 1st draft Teleplay by Mankiewicz and Carabatsos, 9/19/66, 72 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Mankiewicz, Don * Carabatsos, Steven (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (30), DeForest Research (6), General Notes by Gene Coon (2), Notes on Final Draft (3), Notes on First Draft (2). Total Items: 43 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Production Materials: Daily Production Reports (7), Call Sheets (6), Credits (3, 4 copies), Dubbing Schedules (2), Cast (4), Shooting Schedule (10). Total Items: 41 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/22/66 - 10/4/66 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Peters, Gregg * Mankiewicz, Don * Black, John D.F. (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Financial Materials: Daily Budget Reports (3), Production Budget Reports (4). Total Items: 7 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - DAGGER OF THE MIND (Prod# 11)
    - 1) Teleplay, n.d., w/annotations, 64 pgs. 2) Final draft teleplay by Shimon Wincelberg, 07/31/66, w/annotations, 68 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Wincelberg, Shimon (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1) Teleplay by Shimon Wincelberg, n.d., w/annotations, 65 pgs. 2) First draft teleplay by Shimon Wincelberg, n.d., w/annotations, 65 pgs. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1) Teleplay by Shimon Wincelberg, 6/27/66, w/annotations, 64 pgs., 2 copies. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1) Step outline by Shimon Wincelberg, n.d., 21 pgs. 2) Story outline, revised, 03/30/66, w/annotations, 25 pgs. 3) Story outline, 2nd revision, 04/25/66, 14 pgs. 4) Story outline, 05/09/66, 28 pgs. 5) Story outline, 5/2/66, w/annotations, 18 pgs. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Script materials: Revisions, loose pages (65), Comments on teleplay by Shimon Wincelberg (1), DeForest Research (4). Total Items: 70 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Production materials: Shooting schedule (11), Cast list (3), Call Sheets (7), Daily production reports (8), Work Order (1), Credits (3, 4 copies). Total Items: 42 (Box 6, Folder 4)